# 大家好 今天好熱啦 帶釔狗去洗一下澡 你看
Hi everyone. It's really hot today. Let's take the puppy to have a bath. Look!
# 它都不洗澡 不講衛生
He never takes a bath, so unhygienic.
# 現在還不願意去 拉它去它都不願意去
He still doesn't want to go. I'm pulling him but he still doesn't want to move.
# 走
Just go!
# 去 帶你去河邊 走
Go! I'm taking you to the riverside. Let's go!
# 走
Go!
# 快點走 快點 走
C'mon, go! C'mon, let's go!
# 你看 它不肯去
Look! He doesn't want to go.
# 拉它去它都不肯去
He's simply not moving no matter how hard I pull.
# 等下我丟到你河裡去
Don't make me throw you into the river!
# 還不快點 來
Hurry up! C'mon!
# 一身都是
You're covered with,
# 那個 泥土
I mean, with dirt.
# 走
Go!
# 這小狗它都不願意去洗澡的
This puppy doesn't want to take a bath at all.
# 要講衛生 不衛生講怎麼行
Hygiene is important. How can you be that unhygienic?
# 走啦
Let's go!
# 快點
Hurry up!
# 你看 這狗
Look! This dog,
# 從出生到現在都沒洗過澡
has never had a bath since his birth.
# 太髒了它身上
He's so dirty.
# 剛好借了兄弟一點點這個
My buddy just lent me a tiny little bit of, this is,
# 洗狗液
dog shampoo
# 舒不舒服
Does it feel good?
# 舒服吧
Good, isn't it?
# 它身上 還粘了
Something get stuck, stuck on his body.
# 粘了石頭 (註︰語序關係無法直譯，唯有稍稍改動說法)
These are rocks.
# 粘了石頭在這裡
The rocks get stuck on his body.
# 粘了個
The rocks,
# 石頭
get stuck on his body.
# 你看 那麼多沐浴露放上去 泡都沒有的
Look! There's hardly any foam in spite of the huge amount of shampoo.
# 說明就很髒啦 它身上
That means he is really dirty, all over the body.
# 沒事噠 過來
No worries! Come here!
# 它不肯
He doesn't like it.
# 不肯也要洗呀 不肯
Like it or not, I'm bathing you today.
# 那麼髒
You're so dirty!
# 再洗洗 再搞點
Wash again, more shampoo.
# 你看 它老是想跑
Look! He always wants to run away.
# 這樣怎麼行
How can it be?
# 下來
Get down!
# 等下我
Don't make me,
# 等下我 揍你的哦
don't make me beat you up, got it?
# 那麼不聽話
What a naughty boy!
# 還有好多泡
There's still a lot of foam.
# 你看 現在洗的差不多了
Look! We're almost done.
# 菜葉子都有洗到這裡來
A veggie leaf is splashed here.
# 你看 這裡還有一片菜葉子
Look! Here's a veggie leaf.
# 可以了吧 那麼乾淨了
Isn't it good? You're so clean now.
# 你還嫌棄
How disgraceful you are!
# 不可以叫
No yelping!
# 好啦
Alright!
# 洗乾淨啦
He's very clean now.
# 你這邊有那麼多泡泡沒洗
There's still a lot of foam in this side.
# 都沒洗過澡
It's your first bath.
# 知道你身上有多髒嗎
Do you have any idea how dirty you were?
# 你看 我把它放啦
Look! I'm gonna take off the leash.
# 等 等一下讓它乾了之後
I'll, I'll put it on again,
# 我們再把它抓來
when he's dried.
# 好 回家 上去
Alright! Let's go home! Go up there!
# 等下它乾了之後就好啦
Everything is done after he's dried.
# 走 回家
C'mon! Let's go home!
# 你看 把這個狗
Look! We're gonna dress up the dog,
# 把個狗給它穿一下女裝
dress up the dog in girl's clothing.
# 我們穿女裝
If the clothes are on us,
# 太嚇人啦 嘿嘿嘿
it's too scary. Ha ha ha!
# 受不了
Horrible!
# 剛好套在頭上來
I can put it on through his head.
# 你看 這樣就靚了吧
Look! Isn't it beautiful?
# 可以啦 就這樣就可以啦
Alright! It's fine now.
# 這樣就可以啦
It's fine now.
# 這還有一個 還有一個裙子
One more. We have a skirt too.
# 給它套下來
Tuck it into the skirt.
# 這個裙子
What a nice skirt!
# 帥吧
Handsome boy!
# 別動 別動 等一下就好了
Don't move. Don't move. It will be finished in a second,
# 等一下就好了
just one more second.
# 這個小姑娘
This is a lady.
# 很漂亮啊 哦 你看一下
So pretty. Oh! Take look!
# 你兒子
You son,
# 這是你兒子哦 變成這樣子啦
this is your son. This is his new look.
# 它正面多好看
He looks really nice in the front.
# 過來 看一下
Come here! Take a look!
# 可以哦 這樣
It's not bad, c'mon!
# 比以前漂亮多啦
He's so much prettier than before.
# 它裙子不適合它 它老是踩
The skirt doesn't fit him well. He's always stepping on it.
# 它媽都不認識它了
His mom can't even recognize him.
# 誒 怎麼掉了
Ey? Why is it dropped?
# 過來
Come here!
# 揍你哦 等下
I'm gonna beat you up!
# 你看 這下它就方便啦
Look! He feels much more comfortable now.
# 不可以 搞掉
No! Don't take it off!
# 不可以搞掉
Don't take it off!
# 再看一下
Let me watch for a while.
# 可以 這個 這個套裝
This, this suit is really not bad.
# 絕對是
It's undoubtedly,
# 最漂亮的
the prettiest.
# 看
Look!
# 不要動
Don't move!
# 誒呦
Eyo!
# 壞得很
Bad boy!
# 過來
Come here!
# 腳上這個才靚
The ones of the feet are the most beautiful!
# 很委屈 是不是
You suffered a lot, didn't you?
# 有甚麼好委屈的
It's not a suffering at all.
# 你不委屈怎麼辦 委屈我是吧
But if it's not you, then who? You want it be us?
# 你委屈一下就好啦
A little bit of your suffering can do so much good.
# 我穿女裝 會嚇到你的
You would be terrified if I dress up in girl's clothing.
# 你穿一下
So you're a better option.
# 你看一下 它很配合了
Have a look! He's so cooperative.
# 是不是
Aren't you?
# 好配合啊
You're so cooperative.
# 今天 今 今 今天 今天買肉給你吃
Today, to, to, today, today, you'll have meat.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 自由啦
You're free now!
# 你看
Look!
# 他頭也不回
He's not looking back,
not looking back at all!